Inventory of the Archibald Woods Papers 1777-1893, 1783-1846
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Archibald Woods Papers, 1777-1893, 1783-1846.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 W87
2,775 items.
Papers, chiefly 1783-1846, of Archibald Woods of Ohio County, West Virginia. The papers concern his family, the Poage family, and the Houston family, as well as his business dealings.
Baker family,; Morgan family,; Levi Barber,; Daniel Call ,; Philip Doddridge,; Chapman Johnson,; Henry Lee,; James Pindall,; Benjamin Ruggles,; Daniel Sheffey,; John Tyler,; Edgar Campbell Wilson,; George Washington Wilson,; Thomas Wilson,; Archibald Woods.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 2,674 items, 11 May 1940.
Gift: 101 items, 2 January 1942.
Biographical/Historical Information
A Federalist, Woods served in the Virginia House of Delegates and was a member of the Virginia Convention of 1788. He briefly served in the Revolutionary War and later was an officer of the Virginia militia, attaining the rank of colonel before resigning in 1816. Woods was president and a director of the North Western Bank of Virginia. He owned a flour mill, traded whiskey and leased out land. One of the founders of Woodsfield, Ohio, Woods was a land speculator in the military warrant land in the Northwest Territory and bought public land in Ohio and Indiana in addition to having extensive holdings in West Virginia. He was also either a principal or involved in some way with lawsuits to either settle land disputes or to collect money. He promoted the building the Cumberland Road which passed through Wheeling.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, chiefly 1783-1846, of Archibald Woods of Ohio County, West Virginia. The papers concern his family, the Poage family, and the Houston family, as well as his business dealings. Correspondents include Levi Barber, Daniel Call, Philip Doddridge, Chapman Johnson, Henry Lee, James Pindall, Benjamin Ruggles, Daniel Sheffey and John Tyler, Edgar Campbell Wilson, George Washington Wilson and Thomas Wilson.
Subjects dealt with in the collection include banking, cholera, the Cumberland Road, land speculation, pioneer life near Wheeling, West Virginia and in Kentucky and Indiana, formation of and early days in Belmont and Monroe counties, Ohio (including the founding of Woodsfield, Ohio), the Northwest Territory, Indians of North America, family life, marriage and courtship, Virginia militia during peacetime and in the War of 1812, Ohio politics, sale of slaves and the Whiskey Rebellion.
There are also letters of members of the Baker and Morgan families of Fauquier County, Virginia and Wheeling, West Virginia which concern life in St. Louis, Missouri during the 1840's.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically by date.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Baker family.; Morgan family.
Persons:
Barber, Levi.; Call, Daniel, 1765 (ca.)-1840.; Doddridge, Philip, 1773-1832.; Johnson, Chapman, 1779-1849.; Lee, Henry, 1756-1818.; Pindall, James, 1783 (ca.)-1825.; Ruggles, Benjamin, 1783-1857.; Sheffey, Daniel, 1770-1830.; Tyler, John, 1790-1862.; Wilson, Edgar Campbell, 1800-1860.; Wilson, George Washington, b. 1807.; Wilson, Thomas, 1765-1826.
Subjects:
Banks and banking--United States--History.; Cholera--United States.; Marriage--United States.; Slavery-- West Virginia-- History.; Whiskey Rebellion, Pa., 1794.; Virginia--Militia--History--War of 1812.
Geographical Names:
Cumberland Road.; Wheeling (W.Va.)--History.; Kentucky--History.; Indiana--History.; Belmont County (Ohio)--History.; Monroe County (Ohio)--History.; Northwest, Old-- History.; Woodsfield (Ohio)-- History.; Ohio--History.; Ohio County (W. Va.)-- History.; Saint Louis (Mo.)--History.
Contents List
- Appointment of Andrew Woods as sheriff of Botetourt County, Virginia, signed by Patrick Henry, 18 October 1777., 1 page. Pst. of PD. (Folder 1)
- Deed for sale of 440 acres of land in Kentucky County [Kentucky] by Julius Saunders to Andrew Woods, recorded by Levi Todd, 7 April 1779., 2 pages. Pst. of PD. (Folder 2)
- Certificate of land patent to Abraham Vanmetre for 1400 acres of land in Yohogania County [Pennsylvania], signed by Francis Peyton, Phil[ip] Pendleton and Joseph Holmes and witnessed by Sam[ue]l Irwin. Entered with H. Crawford S[urveyor] Y[ohogania] County,3 February 1780., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 3)
- Bill of sale from James halters to Archi[bald] Woods, witnessed by And[re]w Woods,4 August 1783., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 4)
- Bond of James halters to Archi[bald] Woods,15 September 1783., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 5)
  Offering his military warrant and pay for service in the [US] Continental Army in lieu of money owed Woods. Witnessed by And[re]w Woods and Alley [?] McKee. Affidavit by Ebenezar Lane.
- Memorandum of an agreement between Archi[bal]d Woods and George Stricker, 29 December 1783., 1 page. ACy of AD. (Folder 6)
  Concerning land to be located and patented by military warrants and divided between the two men.
- Land grant to Andrew and Archibald Woods for 300 acres in Lincoln County [Kentucky], 20 April 1784., 1 page. Cy of D. (Folder 7)
- Memorandum of John Breckinridge of an account with [Martha (Poage)] Woods, 23 July 1784., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 8)
- Hugh and David Barclay, Rockbridge County, 22 February 1785. (Folder 9)
  Bill of sale to Martha Woods, Botetourt County, 1 negro girl.
- B. H. Pollock, n.p., to And[re]w Woods, Lincoln County, [Kentucky], 30 April 1785., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 10)
  Concerning money and land.
- Bond of Samuel Todd and Nicholas Carper of Botetourt County, Virginia with Martha Woods, 6 May 1785., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 11)
- Bond of Ja[me]s Woods, of Botetourt County, Virginia, with Arch[ibal]d Woods, of Botetourt County, Virginia, 21 May 1785., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 12)
- Power of attorney of John Poage of Augusta County, [Virginia], to Archibald Wood[s],9 November 1785., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 13)
  Concerning land purchased from the military claims of James Ludlow, James Letort and And[re]w Fowler who served in "the old Virginia Regiment under Governour Dinwiddie's Proclamation."
- B[?] Bradford, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 6 April 1786., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 14)
  Concerning land on the Kanawha River.
- Entry by Abraham Nelson for 1000 acres of land [in Kentucky], 6 June 1786., 1 page. Cy of D. (Folder 15)
- Bond of Presley Nevill of Washington County, Pensilvania [Pennsylvania] with Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia] for land in Ohio County. 18 July 1786., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 16)
  Nevill was att[or]ney for W[illia]m Croghan. Witnessed by Jo[h]n Beaver and [?] Heth.
- Bond of Archibald Woods of Ohio County, Virginia with Presley Nevill ( att[orne]y for W[illia]m Croghan) Washington County, Pennsylvania, 18 July 1786., 1 page. AD. (Folder 17)
- Land patent issued by P[atric]k Henry to Martha (Poage) Woods by treasury warrant for 461 acres in Lincoln County [Kentucky], 14 August 1786., 1 page. MCy of D. (Folder 18)
- Bonds of Archibald Woods with Benjamin Atkins and Elizabeth Shearor (administrators of the estate of John Shearor), 16 September 1786., 4 items. (Folder 19)
- Garland Kerr, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia.], to David Enix on Ten Mile, 5 April 1787., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 20)
  Concerning agreement with [Archibald] Woods. Including, ADS, agreement between Kerr and Woods, 6 November 1786. 1 page.
- Moses Chaplaine, n.p. to Archibald] Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 17 December 1787., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 21)
  Concerning a list of land and people which was prepared for the audition.
- Ja[me]s Poage, Mr. G[?], n.p., to Archib[al]d Woods, Ohio County, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1787., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 22)
  Concerning horses. Including A.N. concerning equipment and uniforms for those who join a calvery company. 1 page.
- Elijah Poage, n.p., to Arch[iba]ld Woods, n.p., 29 January 1787., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 23)
  Concerning a trip to Richmond.
- Benj[ami]n Kelley to Isaac Kelley, Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 16 February 1787., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 24)
  Mentions bonds and the postponement of a trip to Ohio County.
  Including N by an unidentified person, n.d., concerning genealogical matters. 1 page.
- Bill of sale from Abraham Byrd, Rockingham County, Virginia to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], for a stud horse, "Leopard." Bond of Archibald Woods with Abraham Byrd, 23 February 1787., 2 items. (Folder 25)
- Promissory note of Wil[lia]m Johnson, n.p., to Archi[bal]d Woods,13 March 1887., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 26)
  Including AN, March 1790, of Johnson with Woods. 1 page.
- Christian Keener, Baltimore [Maryland], to Archibald Woods, Wheelan [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 12 May 1787., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 27)
  Concerning 1000 acres of land in West Virginia.
- Agreements between Benjamin Eakins [Akins] and Archi[bal]d Woods,1 June 1787., 3 items. (Folder 28)
  Concerning the locating and surveying of land in Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia].
- Wm. McMachen [McMechen], n.p., and Arch[ibal]d Woods, Richmond, [Virginia], to James Wood, Lieut. Governour [(sic) Richmond, Virginia], 3 December 1787., 2 pages. L. (Folder 29)
  Asking for help in fighting the Indians and outlining a plan.
- Bills of sale from Geo[rge] Sampson, Northampton County, Virginia, to Archi[bal]d Woods,15 December 1787., 2 items. (Folder 30)
  For 2 slaves, a boy named Littleton and a girl named Pink.
- W[illia]m McCleery, Morgantown [Morgantown, Virginia] [West Virginia] to [Archibald] Woods, [?] Chapline, [?] Yano, & [?] Chambers, 15 February 1788., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 31)
  They were trustees to establish an academy in either Monongalia, Ohio, Harrison or Randolph counties.
- Documents, 10 July 1788- 1 September 1788., 2 items. (Folder 32)
  Concerning a petition to have a ferry across the Ohio River at Short Creek signed by Nathaniel Coolman and John Vanmetre.
- John Steinmetz, Philad[elphi]a,[Pennsylvania], to James Caldwell, Harrison County [now West] Virginia, 14 July 1788., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 33)
  Concerning patents for 10,000 acres of land. Including D of a petition concerning taxation. 1 page.
- And[re]w Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Botetourt County, [Virginia], 15 July 1788., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 34)
  Concerning Indians, land taxes owed by [?] Todd, land dispute between [?] Carper and [?] Moor [Moore], treaty [made by Arthur St. Clair at Fort Harmar] with Indians.
- Charles Lewis, Land Office, Richm[on]d,[Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 30 July 1788., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 35)
  Concerning land in Ohio County.
- Bill of sale (witnessed by Elijaza[?] M'Clandhan and John Poage) from Tho[ma]s Poage to Archi[bal]d Woods,7 March 1789., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 36)
  For a female slave named Phetis.
- James Ross, Washington [Pennsylvania], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 April 1789., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 37)
  Concerning money owed to A. Kirkpatrick by Woods.
- Power of attorney (witnessed by Archi[bal]d Woods and Anna (Poage) Woods) from Stephen May to Robert Woods, 7 September 1789., 1 page. DS. (Folder 38)
  To transfer 331 1/2 acres of land in Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Will[ia]m McClandhan.
- W. Ward, Fayette [County Kentucky], to Archibald Woods, Richmond, [Virginia], 12 September 1789., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 39)
  Concerning Woods' desire to purchase land. Says "our politics are loose, vague, various, and uncertain." Advises Woods to not reject his mother's "precepts because she is a female good sense is the result of a Sound mind which would as soon inhabit a female body as a male. There is no sex in souls."
- Bond (witnessed by Mathew Wilson and Mary Wilson) of Samuel Todd with the executors of the estate of And[re]w Woods,22 September 1789., 1 page. ADS. (Folder 40)
- Bill of sale (witnessed by Willia]m Price, Jr. and Arch[ibal]d Woods) from Henry Guy, Northampton County, [Virginia] to Robert Woods, 29 October 1789., 1 page. DS. (Folder 41)
  For female slave named Lila.
- Agreement, (Witnessed by David Denny, Will[ia]m Denny and Isaac Kelley) between John McFarland, And[re]w Woods and Archi[bal]d Woods,25 December 1789., 1 page. DS. (Folder 42)
  To convey 400 acres of land [in Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia] to McFarland.
- T[homas] Wilson, Margantown [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 3 January 1790., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 43)
  Mentions George Strickler concerning military warrant lands in West Virginia and Kentucky and the non-attendance of Andrew Woods and Archibald Woods as court jurors.
- Henry Bedinger, Shepherds Town [Virginia] [West Virginia] to William Shepherd, Wheeling [Virginia] [West Virginia], 1 March 1790., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 44)
  Asking Shepherd to give him preference if he decides to sell his mill and house.
  Including, N, of Bible verses in a different hand. 1 page.
- David Mitchell, Hampshire [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], to John Lee, Hagerstown, [Maryland], 8 April 1790., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 45)
  Concerning Mitchell's land in Kentucky.
  Including, ALS, John Lee, Hagerstown, [Maryland], to A[rchibald?] Woods. 1 page.
- W[illia]m Wilson, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 23 April [17]90., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 46)
  Concerning Woods' misfortunes, religion, a dispute with [?] Crawford and his baptism of Jenny St. Clair McCulloch.
- J[ame]s Poage, n.p., to Archibald Wood[s], Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], [3 June 1790]., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 47)
  Discusses a move to Kentucky, the death of John Crawford and [William] Wilson.
- Elijah Poage, n.p., Archibald Wood[s], Ohio County near Wheeling [Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 June 1790., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 48)
  Describing Kentucky and Woods' contemplated move there.
- Abram Chapline, Mercer County [Kentucky?], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 July 1790., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 49)
  Concerning land prices in Kentucky near Lexington and Danville.
- Elijah Poage, n.p. to Arch[ibald] Woods, near Wheeling, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 5 July 1790., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 50)
  Concerning Woods' possible move to Kentucky and the price of renting land there.
- Ja[me]s Poage,[Kentucky], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 31 July 1790., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 51)
  Concerning family news and Poage's opinion of Kentucky.
- W[illia]m Wilson, Augusta [County, Virginia] to Archibald Wood[s], Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 24 August [17]90., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 52)
  Concerning religion and family news.
- Henry Walker, Botetourt [County, Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 13 September [17]90., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 53)
  Concerning Kentucky.
- Elisabeth Cloya, n.p., to Archerd [Archibald] Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 16 September 1790., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 54)
  Mostly concerns religion and family news.
- John Poage, Augusta [County, Virginia] to Archibald Wood[s], Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 20 September 1790., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 55)
  Discusses family and neighborhood news including the marriage of Polly Stuart to Ned Hall.
- Ja[me]s Woods, Montgomery County, [Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 9 March 1790., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 56)
  Discusses his business affairs and family news.
- David Shepherd, C[avalr]y Lieut., Ohio County to Capt. Com[man]d[ing] Archibald Wood[s],16 March 1791., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 57)
  Telling Woods to be ready with his party of horses if he receives orders.
- W[illia]m Wilson, Augusta [County, Virginia] to Archibal]d Wood[s], Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 17 May 1791., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 58)
  Expressing concern over Indian threats to frontier. Tho[ma]s Poage has entered Presbytery as candidate for ministry. Discusses religion in Prince Edward and Charlotte. Cousin John Crawford is dead.
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods and [Ann (Poage) Woods], Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 2 July 1791., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 59)
  Concerning his judicial circuit and news of mutual friends in Augusta and Rockbridge [County, Virginia].
- W[illia]m Wilson, Augusta [County, Virginia], to Archibald Wood[s], Ohio County, Virginia, [West Virginia], 8 July 1791., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 60)
  Containing religious advice, and concerning the role of feelings in religion.
- David Cloyd, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 27 August 1791., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 61)
  Concerning money.
- Bond (witnessed by David McWilliams and James Fulton) of And[re]w and Archi[bald] Woods with George Conner and James [Moak?], 9 September 1791., 1 page. (Folder 62)
  For title to 355 acres of land D. Including, ADS, assign (witnessed by George Humphrey) of George Conner.
- [?] to [?], 17 September 1791., 1 page. L. (Folder 63)
  Probably concerning Archibald Woods.
- Geo[rge] Kelley, n.p., to Archebald [Archibald] Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 20 September 1791., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 64)
  Requesting that Woods take the deposition of David Harbinson as evidence in the lawsuit of Kelly vs. Wilson.
- [Thomas Wilson], Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio [County, now West Virginia], 21 September 1791. (Folder 65)
  Concerns family news.
- Agreement (witnessed by Robert and Ja[me]s Poage) between Rob[er]t Poage and Archi[bal]d Woods,12 November 1791., 2 items. (Folder 66)
  To convey from Woods to Poage 100 acres of land [in Botetourt County, Virginia?] and memorandum of money borrowed form Archi[bald] Woods by [James Poage].
- Tho[ma]s Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 4 February 1792., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 67)
  Saying he has declared himself a candidate for the Virginia Senate and asking Woods' help.
- Geo[rge] Jackson, Harrison County [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archabled [Archibald] Woods, Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 26 March 1792., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 68)
  Concerning rations for a militia company and Jackson's campaign for Congress.
- D[avid] Cloyd, Kenhawa [Kanawha County, Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 13 May [1792?]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 69)
  Concerns a move to Kentucky by Cloyd.
- And[re]w Woods, Chambers Burgh [Chambersburg, Pennsylvania], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 5 June 1792., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 70)
  Concerning supplies.
- Robert Wilson, n.p., to William Wilson, Augusta [County, Virginia], 1792 June 22., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 71)
  Describing his school under Mr. Graham.
- W[illia]m Wilson, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 11 July 1792., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 72)
  Concerning his travels among the [Presbyterian] churches. Gives Woods advice.
- Ja[me]s Poage, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 28 July 1792., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 73)
  Concerning a possible move by Woods to Kentucky. Seat of government may be Lexington.
- Thomas Pettit, n.p., to Archable [Archibald] Wood[s],10 August 1792., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 74)
  Requesting that Woods pay bearer money.
- Agreement (witnessed by George Demento and John McKnight) between William Peck and Archi[bal]d Woods,7 September 1792., 1 page DS. (Folder 75)
  Concerning the sale of hogs and corn.
  Including fragment, DS, [part of signature missing] of a petition concerning a ferry across the Ohi[o River] 1 page.
- Ja[me]s Griffith, William Griffith, Charles Prather, Alex[ander] Wells and Geo[rge] White to Charlestown [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, 7 September 1792., 2 pages. LS. (Folder 76)
  Concerning a proposed division of Ohio County.
- Ebenezer [Zane], W[h]eeling[Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archabald [Archibald] Wood[s], Richmond, [Virginia], 18 September 1792., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 77)
- Ebenezer Zane, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to [Charles] Wells and [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 20 September 1792., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 78)
  Concerns division of Ohio County.
- And[re]w Woods, to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Richmond, [Virginia], 24 September 1792., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 79)
  Concerning the division of Ohio County.
- John Connell, West Liberty, [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Wood[s], Richmond, [Virginia], 24 September 1792., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 80)
  Concerning Indian threats.
- Henry Lee, Richmond, [Virginia] to W[illia]m McMachan, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 2 October 1792., 1 page. LS. (Folder 81)
  Sending a muster roll and pay abstract for McMachan.
- W[illia]m Wilson, n.p., to Archibald Woods], member of the House of Delegates, Richmond [Virginia], 16 October 1792., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 82)
  Concerning money Wilson is trying to collect for Woods.
- Ann [(Poage)] Wood[s], Mr. Wilson's [Augusta County, Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Wood[s], Richmond, [Virginia], 27 October 1792., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 83)
  Concerning family news.
- Bond (witnessed by George Baxter and W[illia]m Z Vereker?) of Archi[bal]d Woods and John Davis, 15 November 1792., 1 page. DS. (Folder 84)
  Promising to furnish troops to the state from Ohio, Harrison, Monongalia, and Randolph counties, [Virginia] [West Virginia].
- Agreement (witnessed by Wm. J. Vereker and George Baxter) between Archi[bal]d Woods of Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia] and John Davis of Monongalia County, Virginia, 15 November 1792., 1 page. DS. (Folder 85)
  To furnish troops.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], to Tho[ma]s Wilson, Richmond [Virginia], [1792] December 11., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 86)
  Describing Indian activities, the difficulty of securing provisions because of Anthony Wayne's levies near Pit[t]sburgh,[Pennsylvania], and possible Congressional candidates.
- Henry Lee, Richmond, [Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Ohio [County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 27 December 1792., 1 page. LS. (Folder 87)
  Concerning two companies of Rangers.
- Archi[bal]d Wood[s], Wheelling [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia] to James Wood, 29 December 1792., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 88)
  Concerning activities of and provisions for Ohio County Rangers and mentions Anthony Wayne.
- W[illia]m McCleery, Monongalia County [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia], 10 January 1793., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 89)
  Concerning McCleery's candidacy for U.S. Congress.
- Agreement (witnessed by John McKnight and David McWilliams) between Richard Yeates and Archib[al]d Woods,22 January 1793., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 90)
  To trade to Woods 304 acres of land in Ohio County Virginia [West Virginia] in exchange for 461 acres of land in Kentucky and a female slave.
  Including copy of the above DS. 1 page.
- Copy of bill of sale from Archi[bal]d Woods to Richard Y[e]at[e]s,22 January 1793., cy of D. 1 page. (Folder 91)
  For a female slave named Lila.
- Power of attorney, 22 January 1793., 1 page. DS. (Folder 92)
  (Witnessed by John McKnight, David McWilliams, Jacob Lusk and Hugh McGuire) from Richard Yeates, appointing John McInyre to act in conveying 304 acres of land in Ohio County [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods.
- Bond, 22 January 1793., 2 pages. DS. (Folder 93)
  (Witnessed by John McKnight and David McWilliams) between Archibald Woods and Richard Yeates to ensure that Woods will convey 461 acres of land in Lincoln or Madison County, Kentucky to Yeates.
- Bond, 22 January 1793., 1 page. DS. (Folder 94)